# RIAN MELLOTTE

#### **CONTACT**

8

22 Knocknagreana, Warrenpoint BT343FP



07596255923



rianmellotte@protonmail.com



github.com/RianMellotte



rianmellotte.netlify.app

## **SKILLS**

- HTML/CSS
- · Typescript / JS
- Azure
- C#
- Python
- .NET
- React
- · Git/Github
- Node.js
- NPM
- Self-motivated and driven
- · Leadership
- · Problem solving
- · Quick and adaptive learner
- · Clear and effective communicator
- Working as part of a team
- · Ability to work well under pressure

## **INTERESTS**

I am an avid chess player. I have won both individual and team prizes. I have served as a President of QUB chess club and board member on the Ulster Chess Union. Chess has helped me improved my problem solving skills, patience and concentration.

I also play 5-a-side football a few times a week. This has helped me with team working and communication skills, as generally the better coordinated team wins.

#### REFERENCES

References To be provided upon request.

Experience working in various technical and detail focused roles. Passionate about technology and software development. I offer a unique perspective, having studied creative problem solving through philosophy and chess.

Determined to work hard to learn and develop my skills in programming, through both work and self-study. Visit my personal website rianmellotte.netlify.app for further information and to access my portfolio.

# **EXPERIENCE**

March 2021 to Current

#### Web Developer Forrit

- Full stack developer in team responsible for maintaining enterprise scale website for major UK bank
- TS, HTML, SCSS and Forrit's patented cloud based CMS used for frontend, .NET and Azure for backend and hosting / resource management
- Building interactive components to design specifications provided by client, e.g. calculators, infographics, application forms etc.
- · Upgrading backend processing and adding features to supporting web tools
- · Implementing optimisations for page performance speed, SEO and accessibility
- Certified Microsoft Developer Associate through passing the AZ-204: Developing Solutions for Microsoft Azure exam

September 2019 to Current

#### Developer

- · First class mark for Masters Python module
- · Built Python database analyser and text to speech synthesiser
- Completed course in web development using technologies including HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, Git/Github, Node.js, NPM and PostgresSQL amongst others
- Built and deployed facial recognition app, accessible at: https://facerecognition411.herokuapp.com

September 2018 to September 2019

# Associate PwC Operate

- Financial Crime Analyst for a large investment bank
- · Compiled relevant data, quickly and effectively assessed it, and recorded my findings
- Used analytical skills to ensure that the data did not contain discrepancies and that all of the procedural requirements were met
- · Delivered a number of training sessions to my team

January 2018 to April 2018

# Political Consultancy Intern Stratagem NI

- Conducted research and compiled reports for various projects and clients
- Led office hospitality and assisted in office and event management
- Developed many skills including researching, event management and business management
- · Used initiative both as a researcher and on a number of projects I led or assisted on

# **EDUCATION**

MSc Mind, Language and Embodied Cognition University of Edinburgh

Master of Science with Merit. Completed in August 2020.

BA Joint Honours Philosophy and Politics Queen's University Belfast

First Class with Degree Plus. Completed in June 2018.